<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backlist</title>
    <description>Historians recommend the books they love</description>
    <link>http://backlist.cc</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 05:43:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 05:43:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Histories of Modern Brazil</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As a Brazilian living in the US, Felipe Fernandes Cruz has seen over the past sixteen years a growing awareness about Brazil. The fascination perhaps lies on the fact that while the country itself is becoming more familiar, the story of how Brazil came to be remains a mystery to many Americans, let alone everyday Brazilians – a tale of contradictions within contradictions.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-modern-brazil">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-modern-brazil</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-modern-brazil</guid>
      </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Outside Reading: Wakanda, Food, Native Authors, Civil War</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this first installment of “Outside Reading,” we’ve collected some reading lists from around the web on subjects from Marvel’s Black Panther reboot to the U.S. Civil War, and if you missed it, last week we had our own list from Jacqueline C. Reynoso on “<a href="/lists/american-revolution-in-unexpected-places">The American Revolution in Unexpected Places</a>”.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2016/Arbeitszimmer_des_Alexander_von_Humboldt_in_Berlin.jpg" alt="Painting of Alexander von Humboldt in his study" /></p>

<h3 id="food-anthropology-a-tribute-to-sidney-w-mintzfood-anthro"><a href="http://anthropologyreport.com/food-anthropology-tribute-mintz/">Food Anthropology, A Tribute to Sidney W. Mintz</a></h3>

<p>In tribute to Sidney Mintz, Jason Antrosio collects a list of books and articles suitable for an introduction to food anthropology for <a href="http://anthropologyreport.com">Anthropology Report</a>. Mintz’s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0140092331/ref=nosim/backlist0e-20"><em>Sweetness and Power</em></a> features as a Place to Start on Rachel Herrmann’s “<a href="/lists/histories-of-food-and-hunger">Histories of Food and Hunger</a>”.</p>

<h3 id="introduction-to-the-wakandasyllabuswakanda"><a href="http://www.aaihs.org/introduction-to-the-wakanda-syllabus/">Introduction to the #WakandaSyllabus</a></h3>

<p>Walter Greason has collected books, links, music, and video resulting from his #WakandaSyllabus Twitter experiment for the <a href="http://www.aaihs.org">African American Intellectual History Society</a>. Together they provide context for the new <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/notes/2016/05/when-the-world-runs-out-of-room-for-monsters/482835/"><em>Black Panther</em></a> (and upcoming <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/23/books/black-panther-marvel-comics-roxane-gay-ta-nehisi-coates-wakanda.html"><em>World of Wakanda</em></a>) series as “an opportunity for global audiences to study the traditions of black nationalism, Pan-Africanism, and the variety of African indigenous cultures.”</p>

<h3 id="indigenous-book-club-month-books-by-native-authorsindigenous"><a href="http://www.mprnews.org/story/2016/06/02/books-indigenous-book-club-month">Indigenous Book Club Month: Books by Native Authors</a></h3>

<p>June was Indigenous Book Club Month in Canada, and in recognition <a href="http://www.mprnews.org">Minnesota Public Radio</a> arranged for the compilation of this list of books by Native authors and allies.</p>

<h3 id="must-read-books-about-the-civil-war-eracivil-war"><a href="http://bookriot.com/2016/08/01/100-must-read-books-about-the-civil-war-era/">100 Must-Read Books About the Civil War Era</a></h3>

<p>Liberty Hardy collects 100 histories and novels covering not only the time of the U.S. Civil War itself, but the antebellum period and the war’s consequences as well.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>The painting above of Alexander von Humboldt in his study is Eduard Hildebrandt’s “Arbeitszimmer des Alexander von Humboldt in Berlin, Oranienburger Str. 67” from 1842. Image available from <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Arbeitszimmer_des_Alexander_von_Humboldt_in_Berlin,_Oranienburger_Str._67_(Gemälde).jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a>.</em></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:35:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <link>http://backlist.cc/blog/outside-reading-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/blog/outside-reading-1</guid>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Secret Ballots ’16: Histories of American Politics</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><em>Backlist is seeking election-season pitches for new lists from graduate students, junior, and senior scholars. <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#101;&#100;&#105;&#116;&#111;&#114;&#105;&#097;&#108;&#064;&#098;&#097;&#099;&#107;&#108;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#046;&#099;&#099;">Pitch us</a> your idea for a list (8–10 books on an election-related theme) by September 1!</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2016/Election_Day_1815_by_John_Lewis_Krimmel.jpg" alt="Painting “Election Day in Philadelphia” by John Lewis Krimmel.jpg" /></p>

<p>Every four years, Americans across spectrums of class, creed, and ethnicity go to the polls and vote for a candidate whose presidency, they’ve been promised, will be “historic.” Given the ways that the American past has long been taught, that promise is immediately fulfilled: up until a generation ago, our histories were broken into four year chunks, bracketed by wars, that tracked the rise and fall and rise of our political parties and the white men who led them, and the mostly white, mostly male, voters who put them into office. The last fifty years have fundamentally changed our understanding of that past, however, as American historians – many of them women, many of them black, Latinx, and Asian – have gone back to the archives and made clear all the ways that the history of American political participation is as much one of exclusion as inclusion; as much one of loss as victory; and that every person who casts their ballot – and every woman, person of color, illiterate, or poor person who was denied it – is themselves as “historic” as the individuals who shape American politics in countless other ways.</p>

<p>This fall of 2016, the Democratic and Republican parties are each celebrating their candidates as unlike any past major party nominee for president, while charging that their rivals are trailing disturbing histories of their own. In the hopes of helping to separate the signal from the noise Backlist will present “Secret Ballots”: a series running alongside our regular coverage that will feature scholars’ favorite books, books that distinguish the “historic” that has precedent from the “historic” that represents something truly and powerfully new in American politics.</p>

<p>To that end, we also solicit pitches for lists from historians new to our site. We seek histories of American politics and voting widely defined: not just of presidents or parties or particular elections, but of the groups that fought to vote, that have been denied the vote, that have influenced party politics from beyond the ballot. We’re interested in histories of electoral coverage, histories of technologies that enabled or inhibited particular kinds of democratic participation, and histories of protest. Our plan is that if this three-month experiment in Backlist’s format is a fraction as successful as America’s now-nearly-225 year experiment, it will become a permanent quadrennial feature. So, canvas your bookshelves and <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#101;&#100;&#105;&#116;&#111;&#114;&#105;&#097;&#108;&#064;&#098;&#097;&#099;&#107;&#108;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#046;&#099;&#099;">send your candidates to Backlist</a>!</p>

<hr />

<p><em>The painting above is “Election Scene. Statehouse in Philadelphia 1815” by John Lewis Krimmel (1815), available from <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Election_Day_1815_by_John_Lewis_Krimmel.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a>.</em></p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 04:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
            <link>http://backlist.cc/blog/secret-ballots-16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/blog/secret-ballots-16</guid>
        </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The American Revolution in Unexpected Places</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For most Americans, the mention of the American Revolution can easily bring to mind a slew of notable figures, events, and even regions, such as Boston and its harbor. In recent decades, historians have done much to move past more familiar understandings of the period, often focusing their studies on obscure individuals or settings, but many of these lesser-known subjects still fall within the boundaries of the thirteen British colonies that secured their independence in 1783. The books in the list move beyond the “thirteen colonies” to provide alternative vantage points that help paint a richer, more regionally complex understanding of the American Revolution.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/american-revolution-in-unexpected-places">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/american-revolution-in-unexpected-places</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/american-revolution-in-unexpected-places</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Histories of Peruvian Independence</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Peru achieved its independence in 1824, later than any other mainland Spanish American colony and under the leadership of outsiders like José de San Martín and Simón Bolívar. For decades, historians attributed those facts to a repressive colonial society that had quashed dissent, despite massive rebellions from the mid-eighteenth century on. Since the 1970s, however, other historians have suggested that those rebellions—mostly Indian-led—terrified the country’s white elite, slowing independence’s arrival. The reality was more complex, in large part because of the indigenous Andeans who fought for both sides, for their own ideals of freedom and justice.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-peruvian-independence">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-peruvian-independence</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-peruvian-independence</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Histories of Antarctica</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Antarctica has the shortest human history of any continent on Earth. Despite its short human history and lack of indigenous population, the southern continent has a fascinating historiography. Traditionally, historical interest in Antarctica has focused on exploration, and in particular on the history of the so-called “heroic era” of the first two decades of the twentieth century, but more recent historiography has seen a growth in more critical studies of these expeditions, connections to imperialism and nationalism, and their scientific and literary outputs.
</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/antarctica">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/antarctica</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/antarctica</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Jazz History</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>To repeat one of its favorite metaphors, the literature of jazz history is a thick gumbo of perspectives and forms. This list keeps that unevenness and multiplicity in mind, even if it also favors the work of the “New Jazz Studies” of the 1990s and its heirs. Some readers may want chronological perspectives; others to read secondary texts alongside the primary voices. Or _Choose Your Own Adventure_ and look for order in the shuffle.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/jazz-history">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/jazz-history</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/jazz-history</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Catholicism in Modern Mexico</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The books on this list help explain how an imported and imposed religion succeeded, despite attacks by the Mexican state over the course of the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, revealing how a diverse, internally fragmented faith was remarkably inclusive and responsive to local realities. The Catholicism portrayed here is historically dynamic, unlike the backwards and monolithic Church depicted by earlier scholars. The books included focus especially on the realm of belief and practice among ordinary people, acolytes of the brown-skinned Virgin of Guadalupe or the miraculous Christ of Chalma, to locate what Pope Francis has called Mexico’s religious “idiosyncrasy.”</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/catholicism-in-modern-mexico">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/catholicism-in-modern-mexico</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/catholicism-in-modern-mexico</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Jim Crow</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In some way or another, the authors included in this list grapple with the question: How free is free? They ask what it means for a nation that believes itself to be the model democracy to use lynching, segregation, convict leasing, disfranchisement, debt peonage, race riots, and racist caricatures to control black men and women after abolishing slavery. They also ask how Jim Crow disrupted the interior lives of African Americans who survived it.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/jim-crow">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/jim-crow</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/jim-crow</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Histories of Food and Hunger</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Here’s the thing about histories of food and hunger: they’re tricky to write because food and hunger are everywhere and nowhere. Food is everywhere in the sense that it often gets mentioned in passing in works of history that don’t focus on food. One could say that food _was_ nowhere as of ten or twenty years ago; only a small number of chronological histories existed—and many of them focused on the late-nineteenth and twentieth centuries. More recently, historians have turned their attention to the colonial period and the early nineteenth century, asking questions about race formation, power relations, and environmental changes over time.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-food-and-hunger">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-food-and-hunger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-food-and-hunger</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Museum Histories</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Historians generally agree that museums manifest expressions of colonial scientific enterprises evolving over time. Growing to include millions of objects—including human remains and culturally and spiritually sensitive objects—civic museums in the United States and Europe by the mid-twentieth century had become, for a time, among the most important cultural centers worldwide. This list highlights books exploring how these museums grew to have many of the most important anthropological collections on the planet and how Eurocentric museum practices spread into non-Western places, especially in regions where colonial influence proved strong.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/museum-histories">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/museum-histories</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/museum-histories</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Asian Migrations</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This list merely skims the surface of the rich scholarship on Asian migrations, offering a starting point for curious readers. The books and memoirs here tell many stories—of the mass mobilization of Asian labor for colonial development, the intimate encounters between migrants and immigration laws, the social histories of diasporic communities, and their sense of alienation and negotiated belonging in new, foreign places.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-asian-migrations">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-asian-migrations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-asian-migrations</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of North American Slavery</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Historians of the United States have written and argued more about American slavery than about nearly any other subject, and yet scholarly interpretations of slavery have changed drastically over the course of the last century.  This list does not purport to provide even a smattering of what most scholars would consider the most important works on the subject. But collectively, they hint at where the field has been, demonstrate some of its contemporary evolution, and provide room for the voices of both people who experienced enslavement and artists who have imagined it in especially powerful ways.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-north-american-slavery">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-north-american-slavery</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-north-american-slavery</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Global Histories of Identification and Surveillance</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Never before have our personal identities been scrutinized as they are today. In an age of increasing anxiety and concern for security—especially since 9/11—we are asked to authenticate our personal features on a daily basis, sometimes inadvertently. These books force readers to confront their beliefs and concerns about security and privacy, and make them think twice the next time they look at a camera, type their passwords, or get a new ID card.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/global-identification-and-surveillance">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/global-identification-and-surveillance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/global-identification-and-surveillance</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Off the Silk Road, beyond the Great Game: Histories of Modern Central Asia</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Terms like “Silk Road” and “Great Game” have done a great service in attracting readers to Central Asian history. However, these phrases—both coined by outsiders—have done little to advance an understanding of the societies they describe, one implying an inert timelessness, the other merely a rocky theater for European imperial rivalry. So how can we understand modern Central Asia on its own terms?</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/off-the-silk-road">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/off-the-silk-road</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/off-the-silk-road</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of the Modern Papacy</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We expect the papacy to prize tradition and permanence. Yet, the papacy we know is to a large extent a product of the modern era. As Jesuit historian John W. O’Malley once claimed, the most salient fact of Catholic history in the last centuries is the “papalization” of Catholicism. How did this revolution happen?</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-the-modern-papacy">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-the-modern-papacy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-the-modern-papacy</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of that Supposedly-Fun Caribbean Vacation</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There is nothing timeless about today’s traveling culture. The modern tourism industry stretching from south Florida to northern South America emerged out of a long and complicated history of colonialism, slavery, exploration, and dreams of the exotic. To offer a guide into tourism’s past, this eclectic list of stories challenges us to rethink the meaning of Caribbean tourism.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/caribbean-tourism">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/caribbean-tourism</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/caribbean-tourism</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Histories of the Scientific Revolution</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>While most historians are happy to admit something happened to the study of nature between 1400 and 1700, we remain strangely unable to describe exactly what that something was. The maddening maze of qualifications and uncertainties that riddle our thinking and our prose led Steven Shapin to famously proclaim in his 1996 book, _The Scientific Revolution_, “There was no such thing as the Scientific Revolution, and this is a book about it.” Here are ten more books about the Scientific Revolution—if indeed there is such a thing.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-the-scientific-revolution">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-the-scientific-revolution</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/histories-of-the-scientific-revolution</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Maps: A Beginner’s Cartography</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Maps locate histories—stories about time—in the geographies where they happened. But they also have their own histories, and their historians have spent the past few decades demonstrating just how complicated cartography can be. Maps aren’t just dispassionate depictions of territory, interpreted in the same, self-explanatory way by everyone who looks at them. In short, they are untrustworthy.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/maps-a-beginners-cartography">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/maps-a-beginners-cartography</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/maps-a-beginners-cartography</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Family and Gender in Modern Chinese History</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Family and familial ties are at the heart of Chinese society and culture, and in reflection, historians have created a robust and thought-provoking body of work on family and gender in China. Social history remains the bread-and-butter of scholarship on China, but recent trends like the history of emotion and history of the body are also making themselves felt. This vibrant literature points us toward a Chinese history where women and gender are a persistent and vital part of what Chinese historians do.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/family-and-gender-in-modern-chinese-history">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/family-and-gender-in-modern-chinese-history</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/family-and-gender-in-modern-chinese-history</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The Cultural Cold War</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Between 1950 and 1967, the CIA and the U.S. Department of State took on writers, artists, musicians, and others as junior partners in U.S. propaganda campaigns. Uncovering the history of this rather unlikely branch of U.S. foreign relations has become a major preoccupation for diplomatic historians. Audra J. Wolfe shares ten books that sort it all out.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/cultural-cold-war">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/cultural-cold-war</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/cultural-cold-war</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: U.S. Labor History</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The rise and fall of the American working class has led us to tell ourselves stories about the past to inspire us today. But American labor activists have often mythologized the past to no good end. Many of these books seek to strip away the mythology so that we can learn from the past in order to craft a better labor movement in the present and future.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/us-labor-history">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/us-labor-history</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/us-labor-history</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of American Childhood</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Contemporary American attitudes about childhood are rife with paradox. We’re convinced that our children are overprotected, yet parents find it impossible to step back from the many protective measures put in place over the past century. Here are ten books that can help you figure out how we came to be so confused about childhood.</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-american-childhood">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-american-childhood</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/history-of-american-childhood</guid>
      </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Last Minute Holiday Gift Guide for Historians and the People Who Love Them</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>‘Twas the night before Christmas, and all through the house, historians were worrying about all the things they didn’t read or write that year.</p>

<p>Fortunately, you can help; if by ‘helping,’ we mean ‘pile on more wonderful things to equally inspire and instill tremendous anticipatory guilt for the New Year.’ Backlist has come up with six last minute gifts for the amateur or professional historian on your holiday gift list that will be sure to make them at least smile, with furrowed brow, as the year’s publishing catalogues flip over.</p>

<p>Please note, though, we’ve avoided putting books on this list for two reasons: that’s what the rest of our site is for, and, if you’re a historian’s gifting relative, chances are that they’ve already checked the book you were thinking about gifting them out from the library, and they have a very, very strong opinion about it. So instead we’re helping you to help them to smile. Because even if history feels pretty unrelentingly dark at times, those of us who read and write about it mostly aren’t. And we love a good joke. Like, ‘Did you hear the one about the hopeful solstice holiday that was commodified by the Industrial Revolution and English bourgeoisie?’</p>

<p>Hilarious. And here are some things to commodify and gift.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/?ie=UTF8&amp;keywords=old+book+scented+candle&amp;tag=backlist0e-20&amp;index=aps&amp;hvadid=47411772530&amp;hvpos=1t1&amp;hvexid=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=4416532350766266052&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=b&amp;hvdev=c&amp;ref=pd_sl_3zgqpsywnl_b">Book-Scented Candles</a></strong>: Did you know that you can light your winter with the smell of history? That is, candles that smell of new books, old books, and ancient scrolls, or even particular settings, like mid-nineteenth century American gothic dissolution (Edgar Allen Poe = Cardamom, Absinthe, and Sandalwood). There doesn’t seem to be a candle for Medieval Europe, though, which is probably for the better. Plague, body odor, onions, and incense is a fun candle to imagine; less so to recreate.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss_1?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;field-keywords=reading+glasses&amp;rh=i%3Aaps%2Ck%3Areading+glasses&amp;tag=backlist0e-20">Reading Glasses</a></strong>: It’s time to face the inevitable. Your loved one’s love of history? It’s killing their eyes. Right about now is the time of year when lovers of good books and eight-point font footnotes start taking their glasses off, rubbing their eyes with forefinger and thumbs, and worrying about their next trip to the optometrist. Anticipate this (even if that’s something a good historian never does) and give them the gift that keeps them reading.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>A Premium Information Management Tool</strong>:  The appropriately big ticket item on this list, a premium information management program like <a href="https://evernote.com/?var=1">Evernote Premium</a> or <a href="http://www.devontechnologies.com/products/devonthink/overview.html">DEVONthink Pro Office</a> is the thing your favorite historian has perhaps been hearing about all year, but has been wary of trying, because their price tags are often steep. For Evernote, in December of 2015, it’s $49.99 per year; for DEVONthink Pro Office, it’s $149.99. But what they can get, if you gift it to them, is tremendous: programs that let them paperlessly organize their reading and notes on books and in archives, and the photos of documents and journals they want to collate and put in dialogue with other texts. They can sync online between devices and, in the case of Mac-only DEVONthink, offer an OCR function that scans photographed documents and makes their printed text searchable. Over time, these programs pay for themselves, making connections between unconnected research trips, and facilitating further writing. As the price-tag suggests, this is not something to buy without consulting with your historian. Each program has serious pros and cons, and there are cheaper and less complex options out there (including versions of these products with less features). But if you want to put a spring in your historian’s step, start the conversation. Because if you don’t explain the Cloud to them, someone else will.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://www.standstand.com/">The StandStand</a></strong>: Santa Claus brought one of our editors this lightweight, portable, beautifully-made standing desk last year, and it’s how she knows she was on his “nice” list. Designed by an academic who understands the toll that endless sitting has on the scholar’s body (insert “discipline and punish” joke here), this portable desk will allow your favorite historian to take her reading and writing work to the porch or the dining room table or even the coffee shop — and to stand while she writes for a change of pace.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B006WBPVNW/ref=nosim/backlist0e-20">Bathtub Book Stand</a></strong>: Chances are that your favorite historian already has a book stand. (If not, this blessedly <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B000RO6CEC/ref=nosim/backlist0e-20">simple wire one</a> makes a great stocking stuffer.) But do you know what they don’t have and will give them a funny panic attack when they rip open its wrapping paper? A <strong>bathtub</strong> book stand. Give this one with a smile, and a hand squeeze to show you know their pain. Tell them, ‘I know how much you like to multitask, even when relaxing. No one’s expecting you to bring your library books into the bathroom and cause water damage. Just the latest edition of the <em>American Historical Review</em> so that you can get inspired by your historical nemesis’s latest victory.’ Or, to read the next item on the list, if you want their heart rate to go contemplatively down, not up.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0679731806/ref=nosim/backlist0e-20">Willa Cather, <em>The Professor’s House</em> (1925).</a></strong>: ‘Avoided’ adding books to this list is not the same as ‘not putting books on this list.’ We make the rules, and we bend ‘em for exceptions as on-point as <em>The Professor’s House</em>, Willa Cather’s 1925 novel about an aging American historian who has spent the last many years of his life laboring on a multi-volume history of the Southwest; who has grown distant from his family; who is haunted by the journal of his one-time protege, who found an abandoned Native American plateau city akin to Mesa Verde, and then saw it lost to looting. That journal’s placement in the novel’s structure is fascinating—Cather described it as turquoise set in silver—and its effects on the life of the professor and his family are hauntingly beautiful. It’s up to you whether Cather’s rendering of the professor’s perception of one son-in-law through the veil of anti-Semitic stereotypes reinforces those stereotypes, or is about anti-Semitism itself. (There’s evidence for both, which hopefully suggests the latter.) But in the biggest, most moving sense, <em>The Professor’s House</em> is a sensitive exploration of aging through work, of families being unmade and remade by unspoken tragedies, and of the possibility of a lost past that breaks your heart, but whose memory maybe saves it.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>And if they’re looking a little haggard, and need something a little lighter – ok, a lot lighter – <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316070637/ref=nosim/backlist0e-20">Elizabeth Kostova’s <em>The Historian</em></a> works in a pinch. Dracula + Plot Points Hinging on Shockingly Lax Archival Rules = An Apt Holiday Diversion.</p>

<p>Yes, that Dracula. Happy Holidays, and Don’t Forget to Footnote!</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://backlist.cc/blog/2015-holiday-gift-guide</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/blog/2015-holiday-gift-guide</guid>
        </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Drugs from Ambergris to Zedoary</title>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>These books range widely, from the Pulitzer-prize winning poet Odell Shepard’s Harry Potter-esque history of unicorns and Marcy Norton’s influential recent academic history of tobacco and chocolate to Alexander and Anne Shulgin’s utterly unique guide to various psychedelics and “entactogens” of their own manufacture. What binds them together is a fascination with that boundary-crossing, protean, and endlessly fascinating class of substances we call “drugs.”</p>
            <p><a href="http://backlist.cc/lists/the-history-of-drugs-from-ambergris-to-zedoary">Check out the list at Backlist…</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc/lists/the-history-of-drugs-from-ambergris-to-zedoary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc/lists/the-history-of-drugs-from-ambergris-to-zedoary</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
