<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backlist</title>
    <description>Historians recommend the books they love</description>
    <link>http://backlist.cc//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://backlist.cc//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 06:22:55 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 06:22:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of American Childhood</title>
        <description>Contemporary American attitudes about childhood are rife with paradox. We’re convinced that our children are overprotected, yet parents find it impossible to step back from the many protective measures put in place over the past century. Here are ten books that can help you figure out how we came to be so confused about childhood.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-american-childhood</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-american-childhood</guid>
      </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Last Minute Holiday Gift Guide for Historians and the People Who Love Them</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Twas the night before Christmas, and all through the house, historians were worrying about all the things they didn’t read or write that year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>http://backlist.cc//blog/2015-holiday-gift-guide</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//blog/2015-holiday-gift-guide</guid>
        </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Drugs from Ambergris to Zedoary</title>
        <description>These books range widely, from the Pulitzer-prize winning poet Odell Shepard’s Harry Potter-esque history of unicorns and Marcy Norton’s influential recent academic history of tobacco and chocolate to Alexander and Anne Shulgin’s utterly unique guide to various psychedelics and “entactogens” of their own manufacture. What binds them together is a fascination with that boundary-crossing, protean, and endlessly fascinating class of substances we call “drugs.”</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-drugs-from-ambergris-to-zedoary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-drugs-from-ambergris-to-zedoary</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Monsters in American History</title>
        <description>Oddly, monsters have only recently begun to appear in American historiography, though other disciplines, and in fact other historiographical traditions, have given them much deserved attention. I found few places to start within my own field, especially in the study of modern America. So, I went on a monster hunt.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/monsters-in-american-history</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/monsters-in-american-history</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Modern China</title>
        <description>China’s current rulers, like some past ones, are fond of saying there is a single unified “Chinese tradition” of reverence for hierarchy and tradition. How is it, then, that history reveals a culture with multiple strands, including ones that extol questioning received wisdoms and turning the world upside down?</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-china</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-china</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: Graphic Histories and Memoirs</title>
        <description>Ari Kelman has selected titles below that offer a glimpse at how graphic books can accomplish things that text-based histories can’t – especially how this sort of work can rely on visual metaphors to drive unusually spare narrative strategies.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/graphic-histories-and-memoirs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/graphic-histories-and-memoirs</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of U.S.-Cuban Relations</title>
        <description>How did the United States and Cuba—two nations separated by a mere 90 miles of water—drift so far apart? Why has a country as small as Cuba played such an outsized role in U.S. foreign and domestic politics? Why do the heroes of the Cuban Revolution, by now either long dead or spending their retirement in tracksuits, still hold such power over the American imagination?</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-us-cuba-relations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-us-cuba-relations</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The History of Modern India</title>
        <description>In recent years, the kind of objective truth-telling a professional history implies has been roundly contested by those who feel that elites should not be in charge of writing the history of a large and diverse population. The popular history of India is often told quite differently, and as scholars have attempted to bridge the gap between professional and popular history, many have paid more attention to non-elite and subaltern perspectives.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-india</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-india</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List: The Conquest of the Incas</title>
        <description>To explain how the Spanish conquered the Incas, we must credit the alliances made with the many Indian groups discontented with Inca rule, as well as alliances made with Incas themselves, including Atahualpa. Those alliances then became the foundation of an incredible colonial society, surprisingly just, suddenly violent, that lasted for nearly three hundred years—almost twice as long as England’s colonies in North America.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/conquest-of-the-incas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/conquest-of-the-incas</guid>
      </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Welcome to Backlist!</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Backlist! A publisher’s backlist contains the books that never go out of print. Ours is a place for collections of books that historians might put on their own backlists—or sort into piles their desks and dining room tables. These are the books historians return to again and again, the books they recommend and assign, the books that model what it means to join active conversations about the past, or to ask a new question. We want Backlist to be like a favorite professor’s office: filled to overflowing with stacks and piles sorted according to how they think about a particular region, theme, or question. And we invite you to look around!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>http://backlist.cc//blog/welcome-to-backlist</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//blog/welcome-to-backlist</guid>
        </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
