<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backlist</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://backlist.cc//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://backlist.cc//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 09:59:38 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 09:59:38 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of Modern China</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I took my first Chinese history class in the late 1970s, eager to learn how the country had been reshaped by the revolutions of 1911 and 1949 that had ended dynastic rule and brought the Communist Party to power, respectively. My interest was soon piqued by finding out that long before Sun Yat-sen and Mao Zedong, China had already witnessed many insurrections, some of which had ended in the establishment of new dynasties; whether history called a rebel leader a “bandit” or a “king,” the saying went, came down to whether you won. As someone whose fascination with history began with memorizing the names of English kings and queens during a pre-teen year spent in England and who had always been intrigued by revolutions, I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-china</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-china</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graphic Histories and Memoirs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing:  I had never read a graphic book before I wrote one.  I’m being totally serious: no &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt;, no &lt;em&gt;Ghost World&lt;/em&gt;, not even &lt;em&gt;Maus&lt;/em&gt;.  When I first admitted this to Jonathan Fetter-Vorm, my co-author on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0809094746/ref=nosim/clionautics-20&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battle Lines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he was incredulous.  But after I sent him the script for the first chapter of our book, he believed me.  It was entirely clear, he realized, that I had no clue what I was doing. The only charitable explanation for such incompetence was ignorance.  And so Jonathan decided to play Burgess Meredith to my Sylvester Stallone. He put me on a rigorous training program. I was supposed to consume titles that would transform me into a connoisseur, someone capable of discerning wheat from chaff.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/graphic-histories-and-memoirs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/graphic-histories-and-memoirs</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of U.S.-Cuban Relations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How did the United States and Cuba—two nations separated by a mere 90 miles of water—drift so far apart? Why has a country as small as Cuba played such an outsized role in U.S. foreign and domestic politics? Why do the heroes of the Cuban Revolution, by now either long dead or spending their retirement in tracksuits, still hold such power over the American imagination?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-us-cuba-relations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/history-of-us-cuba-relations</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of Modern India</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;History is among the most violently contested academic subjects in modern Indian politics, which may sound surprising because many of us think of history as a set of settled “facts” that can be established by archival research.  Because of its growing size (India comprises nearly 18 percent of the world population) and its status as the “world’s largest democracy,” India’s history can be told from many perspectives that directly contradict one another.  Writing history is a democratic exercise in India.  Yet, in part because of India’s religious, ethnic, and linguistic diversity, developing a capacious and inclusive account of India’s history has long been the goal of academically trained professional historians.  In recent years, the kind of objective truth-telling a professional history implies has been roundly contested by those who feel that elites should not be in charge of writing the history of a large and diverse population. The popular history of India is often told quite differently, and as scholars have attempted to bridge the gap between professional and popular history, many have paid more attention to non-elite and subaltern perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-india</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/the-history-of-modern-india</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Conquest of the Incas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 16, 1532, Francisco Pizarro and about 160 conquistadors captured an Inca lord named Atahualpa, killed over 2,000 Indian warriors, and conquered an empire that sprawled across the Andes Mountains of South America. The Spanish called that empire Peru. In the decades following, its silver transformed Spain from a crusader kingdom with pretensions of re-taking Jerusalem into history’s first global empire—all because of Pizarro’s sword, his &lt;em&gt;harquebusiers&lt;/em&gt;, and a mystery illness that had laid Atahualpa’s father low. As you may have read: &lt;em&gt;Guns, Germs, and Steel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://backlist.cc//lists/conquest-of-the-incas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://backlist.cc//lists/conquest-of-the-incas</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
